<Document>
# Server rules

  [color=#ff0000]You must be at least 18 years of age to play on this server.[/color] Any attempts to avoid this restriction may result in a ban without warning.

  [color=#ffDD00]Welcome to Quantum Blue. This is a Medium RolePlaying (MRP) server, where everyone is expected to roleplay a character and immerse themselves in the world with the other players.[/color]

  Whether listed in the rules below or not, administrators reserve the right to intervene and assist in the flow of roleplay and gameplay in any way they see fit.

  We are also very welcoming to new players! Spacestation 14 is a nerdy roleplaying game and rules may not be so intuitive, so please take your time reading the rules below and don't be afraid to use the Admin Help (AHelp) chat to ask an admin any questions by pressing the F1 key.

## Community rules
  These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.

  -[color=#ffDD00]A0. Prioritize everybody's fun above all else.[/color]
  -[textlink="A1. Do not commit explicit sexual or erotic acts." link="QuantumBlueRuleA1"]
  -[textlink="A2. Follow our chat guidelines and be respectful." link="QuantumBlueRuleA2"]
  -[textlink="A3. Follow the rules regarding sharing in-round information." link="QuantumBlueRuleA3"]
  -[textlink="A4. Follow proper AHelp etiquette." link="QuantumBlueRuleA4"]
  -[textlink="A5. Do not exploit the game." link="QuantumBlueRuleA5"]

## In-game rules
  These rules apply within the context of rounds.

  -[textlink="B1. Roleplay a believable character." link="QuantumBlueRuleB1"]
  -[textlink="B2. Follow our metashield guidelines." link="QuantumBlueRuleB2"]
  -[textlink="B3. Prioritize roleplaying over winning." link="QuantumBlueRuleB3"]
  -[textlink="B4. Follow our escalation guidelines." link="QuantumBlueRuleB4"]
  -[textlink="B5. Do not act as an antagonist if you're not one." link="QuantumBlueRuleB5"]

## Command, Security, Antagonist and Station AI guidelines
  These roles are held to higher standards of moderation.

  -[textlink="C1. Mindshielded roles guidelines" link="QuantumBlueRuleC1"]
  -[textlink="C2. Station AI guidelines" link="QuantumBlueRuleC2"]
  -[textlink="C3. Antagonist guidelines" link="QuantumBlueRuleC3"]

## Silicon rules
  For players who are silicons, these rules override all roleplay rules if there is any conflict. Silicon rules do not override community rules however. You only are a silicon if the game clearly and explicitly tells you that you are a silicon.

  -[textlink="S1. Silicon definitions" link="QuantumBlueRuleS1"]
  -[textlink="S2. Silicon laws guidelines" link="QuantumBlueRuleS2"]
  -[textlink="S3. Self preservation" link="QuantumBlueRuleS3"]
  -[textlink="S4. Unreasonable orders and exceptions" link="QuantumBlueRuleS4"]

## Space law and SOP
  As part of our identity as a MRP server with higher roleplay moderation and higher emphasis on immersion, we have documents on Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) and Alert Procedure, on top of the usual Space Law. Note that infringements to these are normally kept to in-character punishments only, with the exception of infringements by their enforcing roles.

  -[textlink="Alert Procedure" link="QuantumBlueAlertProcedure"]
  -[textlink="Space Law" link="QuantumBlueAlertSpaceLaw"]
  -[textlink="Standard Operating Procedure" link="QuantumBlueStandardOperatingProcedure"]

  [color=#ff0000]If you have any questions or concerns, please ask an admin via the AHelp (F1) chat.[/color]
</Document>
