<Document>
# Rule B1: Roleplay a believable character

  You must roleplay a character separate from yourself, the player. This is a roleplaying game and we're all playing fictional characters,  try to keep your emotions and actions separate from your own as the player.
    - Try to act in-character and do as your character would in that situation.
    - Let others do their own jobs, only help if requested to or explicitly allowed. Remember that everyone queued up for the role they wish to play and roleplay, and by doing another role's job you are both breaking roleplay expectations and taking away that person's gameplay.
      - A notable exception to this is if a department has no staff. You will not get in trouble for trying to get into engineering to set up power if there is no engineering staff available, for example.
    - Being an antagonist does not allow you to stop roleplaying a character. Determine how your character would react to being given your objectives and work through it appropriately.
      - No matter the odds, you are not allowed to stop roleplaying your character to play like a "can-do-it-all" super soldier that only has their antagonistic objectives in mind.
        - This does mean complying (or defying) security enforcement in a believable manner. Acting suicidal in a cell or trying to break out without any regards to your character's feelings or fears is explicitly forbidden.
        - Do keep in mind that there are a few exceptions to this; A nuclear operative, space ninja, ratking or syndicate agent with a DAGD (Die A Glorious Death) objective are not required to roleplay as civilly as a regular syndicate agent, thief or similar. Be sensible.

## Rule B1.1: Follow naming convention rules.

  You're expected to play a character with a believable name.
    - A lot of leniency is given for this rule, afterall we want players to be as creative as they want with their characters.
    - In-character names must not make obvious references nor be too over the top of a play on words, and must not be obscene. Cheesy names are okay and encouraged, but others such as "Greyson Tidus" or "Quan Tumbloo" are explicitly forbidden. Use the AHelp (F1) chat if you're not sure about your character's name!
    - Be careful when creating a brand new character; When making a new character the game will give you a random name and it'll remain there even after you change species. If you are a human named something like "The Hill of Determination" (a very distinctive diona name) you must pick a new, species-appropriate name.
      - Leniency is also given if you have given them that name for a reason. For example, "My slime person has a thaven name because they were raised by thavens and got to pick their virtue as a name" is a perfectly valid reason to have an unusual name for your species.

## Rule B1.2: Communicate in character.

  Most communications should be done in-character. Don't abuse out-of-character channels.
    - Do not use the Emote channel to bypass an inability to speak.
    - Do not use "Netspeak" in character (lol, brb, wtf, u, etc) unless if in an in-character text-form (Nanochat, letters, drawings or anything for the sort).
    - Do not discuss Out Of Character (OOC) matters In Character (IC).
      - Do not bypass this by clarifying an IC message is actually OOC (example: saying IC "Dude i gotta go i'll brb (ooc)" is not allowed).
    - Do not avoid communications with your fellow players. If someone is speaking to you then you should normally speak back to them.

## Rule B1.3: If you die and return to life, follow the new life rules.

  You must not use information gained while spectating, or information leading to your death.
    - If a player dies (not to be mistaken with entering a critical state), they forget roughly up to 5 minutes up until their death. [color=#ff0000]Please report players who break this rule.[/color]
      - Please note that a cyborg being removed from its chassis is not a death, and it's up to the player whether or not to roleplay a memory loss as consequence.
      - Similarly, an OSI being unplugged does not constitute death.
      - Dionas nymphing does however qualify as death.
    - A character entering critical state and recovered before death can still vaguely recall any events leading up to it, unlike if they died.
      - Important to note that you're still encouraged to roleplay it out to some capacity instead of preparing a very elaborate paragraph to send as soon as you're awake from crit. Abusing leniency about this rule will get you punished.
    - If you have any questions about whether your character should or shouldn't remember something, please ask an admin through the AHelp (F1) chat. As a rule of thumb however: if remembering something would ruin the round for someone, you're probably wrong.

  [color=#ff0000]If you have any questions or concerns, please ask an admin via the AHelp (F1) chat.[/color]
</Document>
