<Document>
# Rule B2: Respect the Metashield

  The Metashield is basically defining what your character shouldn't know, even if you the player knows about it. This page isn't meant to be the be-all end-all of Metashield as you are expected to play for interesting situations and not just to win.
  At the end of the day these guidelines exist to ensure the game is fun for everybody,

## Syndicate agents and syndicate equipment
  - Most crew should know of syndicate agents, but have no reason to suspect them unless officially announced.
  - Security and command know about syndicate agents and the kind of equipment they have access to, but similarly shouldn't be overly paranoid about their existence unless their presence is confirmed on station (for example, seeing a small evidence of syndicate equipment like a syndicate gas mask or piece of clothing shouldn't make security and command believe there are syndicate agents onboard the same way that seeing a blood-red hardsuit or syndicate weapon might).
    - Security should also be aware about syndicate uplinks and check them as standard procedure, but not paranoid enough to check for other equipment unless there is active suspicion of them (chameleon items, disguised weapons, headset keys, etc).
  - Other antagonists that have some syndicate items as part of their equipment (bounty hunter, thief, etc) also have full knowledge of syndicate agents and their equipment.

## Nuclear operatives
  - Regardless of job or role, they are to be referred to in-character as redshells or simply nuclear operatives, never "nukies".
  - Players are encouraged not to take redshell call-outs seriously, but this isn't a hard enforced part of the metashield.
  - Most crew should have heard of nuclear operatives and know they target NT affiliated stations, but have no reason to be paranoid about them unless officially confirmed.
  - Security and command both know about nuclear operatives and that they want the station's nuclear authentication disk, and per standard operation the disk must never be left alone.
    - Taking additional measures to defend the disk without confirmation of nuclear operatives is considered a violation of this metashield.

## Thieves
  - Thieves themselves are in-character considered to be generic and nobody (crew or otherwise) should expect them to have anything out of the ordinary.
    - This means that their stealthy hands and their kit are completely metashielded.

## Zombies and initial infected
  - Zombie viruses are known about by most regardless of role or job and so is it's cure.
  - Security and command personnel know nuclear operatives have access to samples of the zombie virus and do sometimes employ it in their operations.
  - Initial infected are completely metashielded. The only thing that can break this metashield is if the initial infected admits to carrying the zombie virus, or once another initial infected turns.

## Space ninjas
  - Most crew know about them and their targetting of NT stations.
  - Security and command knows what kind of equipment they use and their sort of capabilities, but their objectives are strictly metashielded.
    - This means that trying to "camp" criminal record computers, announcement consoles, the RND server and other objectives is strictly forbidden.

## Changelings
  - Most crews know about changelings.
  - Security, command and medical personnel know about testing changeling blood in a centrifuge.

## Replicators
  - Security knows about them, replicator tiers and how they generally operate. Including the fact that they're not inherently hostile.

## Eeeps, ratkings and other vent mobs
  - Nothing about these antagonists is metashielded.

## Wizards
  - Not metashielded, as they're slanted for removal eventually anyways.

## Xenoborgs
  - Most crew only vaguely knows about their existence.
  - Security and command are aware of their existence, the mothership, the crew-to-borg conversion and the kind of borgs/weapons they have.

## Conspirators
  - Not metashielded.

  [color=#ff0000]If you have any questions or concerns, please ask an admin via the AHelp (F1) chat.[/color]
</Document>
