<Document>
# Rule C1: Mindshielded roles

  Mindshielded roles (which includes all of command and security) are given much less leeway when it comes to roleplay and escalation. As command or security you are a "light" dungeon master, and your actions can shape the course of the round for many other players. Be responsible.
    - As per the mindshield's ingame description your mindshielded character must have unquestioned devotion to Nanotrasen.
      - Your character is presumed to be sane, competent in their duties and able to make decisions to the benefit of the station. You are roleplaying someone working a job, your character wouldn't have been hired to do it if they weren't fit for the job.
      - Giving away traitor objective items and sensitive equipment should be seen as a last resort to these roles. Your character should value them deeply, no matter their actual value.
        - Leeway can be given in [color=#ff0000]extreme circumstances[/color] of emergency/crisis.

  Unlike most other roles, your command/security characters are required to know and follow Quantum Blue Space Law, Standard Operating Procedure and Alert Procedure with good intent.

  Circumstances may appear where violating these documents is accidental or unavoidable. This is appropriate as long as they are making an effort to roleplay and follow the documents to the best of their known ability.

# Rule C1.1: Command guidelines

  As a command member you are expected to command your department first and foremost. [color=#ff0000]Do not pick command roles with the intention of playing a department only with more toys and priviledges. You WILL get in trouble for this.[/color]
    - Heads of departments are expected to pay attention to communications to the best of their ability. It's understandable to not be able to keep up through a chaotic shift, but you should always be prioritizing communication over direct work.
    - As the head of your department you must try to delegate tasks and solve disputes to the best of your ability. A head of security must, for example, be ready to delegate tasks to officers or groups of officers as new issues show up. Remember that your role is commanding and leading.
    - While the head of personnel is the main venue for hiring new workers and assigning new jobs, the heads of any department are allowed and encouraged to promote and demote staff as needed. Remember that you have an ID console in your office!
      - As a head of a department you are also expected to try to point acting positions to crucial roles in case of their absence. For example, the CMO should try to promote a medical doctor or paramedic to chemist if they don't already have one. Doing those jobs yourself should be left to a last resort.
    - Heads of departments are expected to report criminal activity and cooperate with law enforcement when possible.
      - Head of departments are however NOT allowed to valid-hunt and go out of their way to assist security. This will get you in trouble.
      - This also applies to captains. Even as the captain, you are explicitly forbidden to "frontline" against antagonists. You are a commander and leader, not a soldier.
    - If you need to leave the round, try to promote somebody to an acting head position if possible. If not, notify the rest of command as well as your department prior to entering cryo.

# Rule C1.2: Security guidelines

  As a security member you are held to the highest level of scrutiny over matters of space law. Space law isn't normally matter of admin intervention, but not following it as a member of security will get you in trouble.
    - Security personnel are still expected to roleplay a believable character. Just because your job is to oppose antagonists doesn't mean you're allowed to forego roleplaying in favor of winning. Roleplaying should still be your priority, ALWAYS.
    - Even as a member of security, you must follow alert procedure chain of command. Meaning for example: During code violet you are to follow the CMO's orders before the HoS's own.
    - Members of security are to follow server rules of escalation very strictly. [color=#ff0000]Engaging a target without escalating will get you rolebanned.[/color]

  [color=#ff0000]If you have any questions or concerns, please ask an admin via the AHelp (F1) chat.[/color]
</Document>
