<Document>
# Rule C2: Station AI

  Despite being subject to all the same rules as other silicons (as listed in the silicon rules category), Station AIs are held closer to standards of a dungeon master than a regular silicon role.

  The stipulations in this rule apply both to a crew-aligned standard Station AI, as well as any that may get converted to antagonist via ion storms or other forms of law changes.

  As the Station AI you control many devices on the station and in many ways have similar responsibilities and capabilities as the Captain. Leeway is given about following silicon rules if it's in favor of fun and a better round for everyone. This effectively means taking into account standard escalation rules even if your laws technically allow you to skip them.
    - This means a subverted AI must have some restraint even if their lawset allows for extreme measures. For example: Being given the Syndicate lawset may allow you to severely cripple Security unprompted, but you may prefer to follow standard escalation rules for the good of everyone involved.
    - A subverted AI is however allowed to escalate their actions to the current situation of the station. For example: You have the Antimov lawset, and either the entire station is collapsing or known Nuclear Operatives are raiding the station. In this situation you are allowed to act out your lawset to its fullest extent.
    - As the Station AI, your responsibilities with Cyborgs is similar to department heads' and their staff. This means you are expected to communicate with your Cyborgs and delegate tasks before doing any yourself.

  Despite your capabilities as the Station AI, it's important to remember that you are one of many players, and unless the entire gimmick of your lawsets revolves around it, you should avoid doing crew members' jobs in their place without request or explicit permission.
    - For example: If Engineering personnel is currently dealing with a gas leak or similar station integrity issue, avoid bolting doors or otherwise interfering without communication first.
    - Another example: If you witness a crime, report it to Security personnel and avoid marking their criminal status yourself. Keep to your lane and assist security, not do their job for them.

  Station AIs are also expected not to valid-hunt or otherwise powergame.
    - Valid-hunting as the Station AI can involve being paranoid about threats under code green, stalking individuals suspicious of a crime without proper request from security to do so, bolting doors without reason, etc.
      - Exceptions to this can involve for example trying to bolt doors to prevent a criminal fleeing from security from escaping, blocking in a criminal after spotting a break-in or murder while waiting for security to arrive, or stopping known Nuclear Operatives to the best of your ability.
      - Do note that shocking doors and similar lethal methods can harm many crew members and for most benign lawsets they should be seen as a last resort.
    - Preemptively activating turrets and bolting doors without a known, significant threat (whether in the AI Satellite or elsewhere) is considered powergaming.

  [color=#ff0000]If you have any questions or concerns, please ask an admin via the AHelp (F1) chat.[/color]
</Document>
