<Document>
# Rule C3: Antagonist guidelines

  [color=#ffff00]Being an antagonist does not allow you to stop playing a character. Determine how your character would react to being given these objectives, and work through it accordingly.[/color]
    - Being an antagonist doesn't exempt you from rule 0. You are allowed to find any way to complete your objectives so long as you're not ruining the round for others. This isn't a competitive game, it's a roleplaying game and considering other people's fun is part of it.
    - Antagonists are free to complete their objectives through committing proportional damage. Through roleplay, damage becomes proportional. Example: Holding the singulo hostage for a theft objective is acceptable, while simply singuloosing without escalation is not.
    - Round removing players unrelated to your immediate objective should always be avoided. Crew that do not make an attempt at self preservation, or engage in valid-hunting, are exempt from this.
      - Round-ending or extremely high impact antagonists such as Nuclear Operatives, Initial Infected and Die a Glorious Death traitors are exempt from this.
    - You should not abuse the power of your role to grief other players. For example, a ninja using their abilities to play "you can't catch me!" with security, completely foregoing the roleplay role of a stealthy ninja, is blatantly against the rules.
      - Similarly, abusing the lack of security (especially at lowpop) to "take over" the station or run around blatantly committing crimes will not be tolerated.
    - Other antagonists are not necessarily your friends. Unless explicitly a group antagonist (replicators, nuclear operatives, conspirators, etc), other antagonists may kill or steal from you for their own advantage.
      - Team antagonists must never turn on each other, barring exceptionally rare roleplay exceptions.
    - No antagonist may loiter or camp around arrivals or cryosleep areas of the station for the purposes of antagonist action towards newly-spawning players.
    - Antagonists should not seek to extend the length of the round unreasonably, where possible.
      - This includes repeatedly recalling the evac shuttle in order to complete their objectives.
    - Antagonists may not bring the round to a close without in-character or objective-related justification as a result of their antagonistic action. While this is largely subjective and not all actions will always cause command to call for evac, antagonists should avoid engaging in potentially round-ending behavior without reason.
      - Any sabotage of critical station infrastructure (power production, cargo operations, armory contents) is covered by this rule.

  [color=#ff0000]If you have any questions or concerns, please ask an admin via the AHelp (F1) chat.[/color]
</Document>
